Labor Editorial Files 5693
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Labor Editorial Files
1900-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Labor Magazine
5693
24.5 cubic feet
24.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Files of Edward Keating and John Baer of the magazine Labor.
5689679
Scope and Contents
This collection is divided into two main series. First, the files of Edward A. Keating, Editor of Labor magazine and second, the files of John Baer, Labor Cartoonist. The collection includes correspondence, original sketches and cartoons, photocopies of published cartoons (other than Baer's), articles, memorabilia and photographs.
Edward Keating's files include correspondence, arranged chronologically, and editorial files, arranged alphabetically by subject. John Baer's files include correspondence, biographical information, articles, clippings, memorabilia, and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5693 G: Labor Editorial John Baer Cartoons
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 12, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 12, 2019
Baer, John.; Keating, Edward, 1875-1965.; Labor magazine
5689679
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  April through Oct; Military Reports and correspondence re to William C. Harllee, Major, U.S. Marine Corps, (Later to become Lt. Col. (1919)). Notable commendations for service, signed by Assistant Secretary of War Breckinridge.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  May-Dec; Correspondence between Keating (then Chairman of the Railroad Organizations Campaign Committee) and E.J. Manion, Secretary, Railroad Labor Chief Executive Organization, re meeting in Chicago on May 21, 1920 where political platform was established; Also contains correspondence to Keating as Manager of the Plumb Plan League from E.J. Manion on RED letterhead re results of meeting at Chicago; Correspondence between Manion and Keating re selection of Mr. Glenn E. Plumb as General Counsel for the 16 Associated Organizations, and list of pledgers to support the Plumb Plan.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Jan-Feb; Correspondence between Keating and Manion re Manion denying to make $1000 pledge to the Plumb Plan
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Jan 1st-March 13th; Contains large folder labeled "Report of Operations and Training, 15th Regiment, U.S. Marine Corps, Jan.-March 13, 1922 personal copy of Lt. Col. Harllee;" detailed report of Operations of 15th Regiment in Eastern District Dominican Republic re bandit situation by William C. Harllee; copies of the 15th Regiment Newsletter, Oct. 29, Nov. 12, 1921; correspondence and reports also re bandit insurrection in Eastern District Dominican Republic (1921); summary of known casualties occurring in the Eastern Districts during period of Sept. 29 to Dec. 1921, San Pedro de Macoris, Jan. 4, 1922 by Wm. Harllee; Correspondence between Harllee and Keating containing a copy of the Naval Omnibus Bill (marked on page k, pensions) postmark 1926; transcripts of boards investigating Marine caused death of Dominican Republican natives, all containing some correspondence of Harllee as regimental commander, March 1922; report commending General Harllee re Patrol Scout Training, Dec. 5, 1921; Report of operation and training from Jan 1st to March 13, 1922 from District Commander Harllee to commanding general; miscellaneous maps of portions of the Dominican Republic; remainder of the correspondence ^g_ Harllee and his regiment had eliminated most of the bandits, but had also molested innocent sugar cane workers; (the only apparent link between Harllee and Keating so far is that one letter postmarked 1926); many reports of troop movements, etc., could not help noticing confidential reports on native informants and coded missives.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Jan 3rd-Dec 11th; Clipping and accompanying correspondence (Dec.1923) re Huey P. Longs endorsement for Governor of Louisiana by Labor; "An Open Letter" from Alvin Moore (Republican candidate for Congress, from the First (Seattle) District of Washington) re_ "A solution of our National Transportation Problem" June 15, 1923, for nationalization of the railroads; Miscellaneous requests for subscriptions; Miscellaneous requests for 'Mat Service' of Baer's cartoon (1923); correspondence between William E. Sweet, Gov. of Colorado and Keating re address for 50th anniversary of the BLF&E, Nov. 1923 and misc. telegrams; Dec. 3, 1923 reporting events of the 50th anniversary of the BLF&E, evidently the "big party" was a success; further note-there are a lot of telegrams from around the U.S. re_ some insurance, most report same success; correspondence from John C. Ready, President, System Federation #17, Secretary-Treasurer District H3, I.A.M. to Editor, Labor re request to print article presumably on a strike involving IAM, Dec. 6,1923; correspondence from League of Women Voters to Editor of "Labor" re request by League to publish articles in Labor; Handwritten correspondence (Dec. 1923) from Benjamin Judkins to the editor, letter sent with enclosures (newspaper clippings), both letter and clippings are re the apparent secret sale of land near San Diego by said city, apparently the issue is acquisition of water and etc. rights; also an editorial on capital accumulation and too powerful business interests in California.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  December 12th-29th; Correspondence from Wade Shurtleff to J.A. Lecher (Dec.12, 1923) re_ support (assume by subscription) for Labor in Ind.; Correspondence to C.A. McDonald, Secretary-Treasurer, Missouri Pacific System Federation from C.A. Newton (U.S. House of Rep.), Joseph A. Meed (U.S. Senate), L.C. Dwyer (Senate) Harry B. Hawes (House) and Selden P. Spencer(Senate) - all Congressmen from Missouri re increase in wages for Postal Employees; correspondence from B.M. Jewell, President, RED to Keating (Dec. 12, 1923) re one Mr. McAdoo and "How he got started to Knoxville, Tenn." Correspondence from J.H. Rae to Keating (Dec. 13, 1923) re_ delivery of handwritten letter of Senator Frank B. Willis (Dec. 3, 1923) -Willis contends will not support child labor law because unconstitutional and upholds Supreme Court decision - Rae is critical of the decision and Willis; Memo to Willis and Lovell (Dec. 14, 1923) re lobbying of Scott Wolff for bill to prohibit interstate traffic of strike breakers, from Keating; Press releases (Dec. 1923) re referendum for American Peace Award (Committee consists of Leonard Hand, Mrs. FDR, Henry Stimson, Elihu Root, etc.) unclear of what referendum is for; Correspondence from Keating to B.M. Jewell re tariffs and Keating as a free trade advocate; correspondence from Jewell to William Johnston (Pres., IAM) and J.D. Noonam (Pres., IBEW) re tariff protection; correspondence between Keating and I. Derrickson, Gen. Secretary-Treasurer, Order of Railroad Telegraphers re appellation of U.S. Railroad Board; Correspondence from Keating to J.H. Rae re constitutionality of child labor law; from W.W. Warwick, Oficina del Agente Fiscal, Panama, to Keating re Herbert Brews attack on Warwick; from Esther Everette Lape to Keating (Dec. 17, 1923) re attempt to secure ballot printing for American Peace Award in Labor, includes description of award, set up by Edward W. Bok offering $100,000 for the best, practical plan by which U.S. may cooperate with other nations and achieve peace in the world; From William McAdoo to Keating re McAdoo's speech Labor printed; Between C.A. McDonald (Sec.-Treas., Fed. #2) and Keating, Dec. 1923, re private vs. government ownership of the railroads; From Robert McKinley, (Sec.-Treas., Texas State Fed. of Labor) to Keating re policy platform adopted by above at labor political conference, includes typed copy of platform; from George E. Sloan, Editor in Chief of the Si-De-Ka, accompanying enclosures from said publication re Labor, Dec. 23, 1923; from (unreadable) to Keating, Dec. 23, 1923 re the sad fate of C.A. Phelan, former General Manager Missouri and North Arkansas Railroad; from Wayne B. Wheeler (General Counsel of the Anti-Saloon League of America)to Keating re prohibition; from Jewell to Keating re success of meeting of the conference for progressive political action in Chicago; from Jewell to Keating re endorsement of McAdoo's candidacy.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Press release, re Locomotive Firemen's "Birthday Party."
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  January 1st-12th; Correspondence from John C. Ready, President System Fed. #17 to Keating re article by Schlefer to be printed in Labor, "A Connecticut Labor Trial."; from Keating to Gov. of Colo., Sweet and Attorney General of Colorado Wayne C. William, Jan. 2, 1924 re decisions on the "Rio Grande case"; letter addressed to McAdoo and Keating requesting copies of McAdoo's San Francisco speech; correspondence from D.B. Robertson (Pres. BLF&E) to Keating re New York Central Rail Strike, Jan.4, 1924; from Keating to B.M. Jewell, Jan. 7, re Senator Lafollette and political infighting in the Congress; Telegram from Charles MacGowan to Labor re attempt of the milk producers (in process of strike) to get recognition from AFL, Jan. 75 1924; correspondence from McGowan to Arther E. Holder, Sec. Conference for Progressive Political Action, Jan. 9, re McGowan's turning down request to appear at Conference; correspondence from Arthur Keep, Editor, Telegrapher Journal, Jan. 75 re Mr. McNamee (who at one time was an alcoholic and now 'stays in his shell because of the hang-over from his past' ). Correspondence from E. Davidson, General Secretary & Treasurer IAM to Sen. Hiram Johnson, Jan. 10, re the Mexican situation which is evidently U.S. covert operations to overthrow a "constitutionally elected" President Obregon who is sympathetic to labor; between R.E. Moon, Chmn. Missouri State Legislative Bd., BLF&E and Keating re amendments to the Constitution of the State of Missouri, Jan. 5; between Keating and C.W. Maier, Special Rep. to the BLF&E re politics in general and more specifically the chances of the Democratic Party in national elections; from Keating to Daniel Roper, Jan. 11, re once again the drunken part of Robert McNamee; correspondence from Wayne Williams, Attorney-General of Colorado to Keating, Jan. 8, re the "Rio Grande" issue, some type of re-organization plan and "juggling" of the railroads; correspondence and clipping, Jan. 18, from Keating to William C. Lyons re McAdoo, candidate for Democratic presidential nomination.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  January 14th-23rd; Correspondence from John E. Mankin (U.S. House of Rep.) to Keating re the scoop on the finances of Secretary Mellon; from W.S. Stone, Grand Chief of Brotherhood of Locomotive Enginemen to Keating, Jan. 16 re H.M. Curry's (Gen. Mechanical Superintendent-Northern Pacific) forced resignation; from Arthur Keep, editor Labor to Keating re more on Robert McNamee; from William G. McAdoo to Keating re_ a publication called "A History of Organized Felony and Folly;" Speech of Gov. John J. Blaine on the 50th anniversary celebration of the BLF&E at Milwaukee; Correspondence from an unidentified signature to Keating Jan. 22, re_ the M&NA Railroad and the strike of that railroad, also contains an enclosure - a motion for postponement in the Boone Circuit Court of Clay Holt against J.D. Jones and others, and also a handwritten letter and financial information on the M&NA (The Missouri and N. Arkansas RR); from D.B. Robertson, Pres. of the BLF&E to Keating re settlement reached on the New York Central Lines, Jan. 23, enclosed is a mimeo copy of the settlement and correspondence on same issue.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  January 24th-28th; Correspondence from William McAdoo to Keating, Jan.25, re the Mellon Plan; Between Arthur Keep and Keating re European investment into U.S., the death of capitalism, etc.; From Ex-Congressman Alim Moore (Seattle) to Keating re_ solution to the railroad problem; From D.B. Robertson and L.D. Sampson, Chmn. Valparaiso University Alumni, Jan. 28, re Sampson requests to help in pro-labor activities; From R.S. Jones (Wash. Office, McAdoo for President Comm.) to Keating re Jones's switch in support of McAdoo.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  January 29th-31st; From Benjamin Judkins to Keating, Jan. 29, re_ that old water issue in California, enclosed many newspaper clippings about the water issue; from Judkins to Warren G. Harding (President) re_ the water issue in San Diego.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Feb. 2nd-8th; Correspondence from Murray E. King to Keating, Feb. 2, re the state prison manufacturing affair; from Keating to J. Ramsay McDonald re_ the purpose of Labor; from James K. Lindley (ORC) to Roy Fitzgerald (Cong. 3rd Ohio Dist.) re_ Workmen's Compensation Bill; from William McAdoo to Keating re editorial in LA Express favorable to McAdoo; From Keating to Wayne C. Williams, Att. Gen. Colo., re previous issue of railroad land purchase, Rio Grande, also re-organization; between Keating and J.T. Vanakle Feb. 4, re M&NA default on loan and attempted investigation; from Emil 0. Jorgensen to Keating regarding one Professor Richard T. Ely who Jorgensen regards as 'one of the worst enemies of economic freedom this nation has ever seen," the whole plot is laid out in Feb. 5; from Arthur Keep to Keating, Feb. h re_ the "world bank" and some shady dealing with Horn blower, Weeks & Co.; From the Labor Bureau to Keating re_ attempts to increase circulation of their own, "Facts for Workers", also enclosed a questionnaire as a sample copy; from Keating to Hon. George C. Record, Feb.55 suggesting Lafollette as a 3rd party candidate for President; clippings on "Happy Home Dresses," possibly in relation to prior clothing scandal; From Keating to Sen. Thomas Wake, Feb. 6, re Strauns shady connections and some relationship to Coolidge campaign; from Keating to Wayne C. William, Attorney General, Colorado, re the Rio Grande re-organization scheme; Advance press release dated Feb. 7, entitled "The Pennsylvania Railroad Shopmen Betrayed," article written by H.S. Jeffrey who enacted suit against shopmen for recent strike; from James Couzens, Senator-Michigan to Keating re New York tax reduction motivations; from Charles McGowan to Keating re the endorsement of proposed political candidates.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Feb. 9th-16th; Correspondence from Keating to Senator Lafollette, Feb. 9, re M&R propaganda on the Chesapeake & Ohio; from Keating to John F. McNamara, Editor, BLF&E Magazine, re Teapot Dome scandal investigation; From T.C. Cashen, President, Switchmen's Union to Keating re the BRT's use of private investigations under the guise of organizer, basically factional infighting; Confidential correspondence from W.G. Lee to F.W. Morey, re an enclosed report on the Switchmen's Union in Birmingham and the rivalry there with the BRT - report is signed by Roy C. Smith (Organizer BRT) and addressed to W.G. Lee, President of BRT; from Henry M. Rathbone (HOR-ILL) to Keating, re_ Rathbone request for Keating to hear his first speech in Senate; an original copy of the Birth Control Herald (Jan. 1924)published by the Voluntary Parenthood League, NYC, emphasis on Cummins-Vaite bill to free up contraceptive knowledge; from Basil M. Manby, Dir. of Peoples Legislative Service to Keating re Committee on Interstate Commerce of Railroad Propaganda; from Keating to Wayne Williams re the Rio Grande issue.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Feb. 18th-25th; Telegram from Charles J. MacGowan to Keating re McAdoo's candidacy; from W.W. Norton, Publisher, People's Institute Publ. Co., to Keating re_ People's Inst. Pub. Co.; From Charles McGowan to Keating reporting on the St. Louis Labor Conference, 1924; Miscellaneous correspondence re the death of Jack Dermody; from McAdoo to Keating re corruption on the railroad lines and congressional activities on the Esch-Cummins Act; from Keating to Lafollette re_ federal loan to the Missouri and North Arkansas Railroad, also correspondence on same issue from S.J. Venable to Keating; from Wayne Williams to Keating, re William's decision not to pursue investigation of "Rio Grande" controversy
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Feb. 25th; Correspondence between Keating and Williams re the Rio Grande issue and dismay of McAdoo.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  March 1st-14th; From D.B. Robertson, Pres. BLF&E to Keating re_ to Pacific Bulletin article where Labor is accused of falsifying information; from Keating to George M. Shriver, Senior VP, Baltimore & Ohio Railroad re Shriver's finances; partial report re the Constitutional Convention in State of Missouri; from Jesse Kennedy to Keating re_ corrupt political system, additional correspondence from Kennedy re_ an initiative and referendum on alcohol prohibition; from Judson King, Director of the National Popular Government League, to Keating re opposition to Section 23 of the Immigration Bill; from Mr. Hunter, involved with the company union of the Great Northern Railroad, circular criticizing labor's stance against the railroad, also a partial stenographic transcript of relevant section of the hearing before the Railroad Labor Board, sent by McGowan to Keating in response to the circular; from Andrew R. McDonald to Keating re the Esch-Cummins Law, also called the Transportation Act of 1920; between Keating and McAdoo in re the political campaign and the effect of the oil scandal on the Republican Party; between Keating and Williams re to attempts to secure investigation in the Congress of the Rio Grande reorganization; Martin F. Ryan, Pres. of the Brotherhood. of Railway Carmen to Keating re_ political machinations which may lead to the re-election of Calvin Coolidge.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  March 15th-27th; Correspondence from Marvin Gates Sperry, National Pres., Private Soldiers' and Sailors' Legion to Keating expressing their organizations affiliation with all pro-labor factions; from Keep to Keating implying possible collusion and graft between Coolidge administration and Henry Ford; between I.D. Mumby and Keating re_ possible candidacy for presidential office of Robert Lafollette; between Keep and Keating re the St. Louis conference; from Wayne Williams to Keating re the Rio Grande issue and possible VP nomination for Governor Sweet of Colorado; between Keating and H.E. Wills re_ a Knoxville, Tenn. publication called the Journal in reference to "club purchasing of carloads of coal"; from Judson King endorsing E.D. Morel for the Nobel Peace Prize - result of the election on the Great Northern RR sent to Keating by T.C. Cashen, Pres. Switchmen's Union.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  March 28th-31st; From T.F. Shuman, Gen. Chmn. ORC, to Keating re H.G. 6865, the Rainey Bill; from W.S. Stone, BLE to Keating re the turn around case in reference to the Denver & Rio Grande Western RR; between Keating and Williams re the presidential situation as it relates to Ralston and Cummings; C.J. Ross to Keating re an enclosed copy of a resolution to be presented at the coming session of Grand Div.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  April 1st-25th; Telegram from Keating to H.E. Miles, Chairman of the Fair Tariff League re conditions for a fair tariff; From Esther Everett Lape, member-in-charge, American Peace Award to Keating re the publication of some old peace proposals from prior contest; from Arthur Keep to Keating re possible attempt by the railroad to turn workers away from progressives in the Congress; from J.T. Venable to Keating re exposure of the failure of the Missouri & Arkansas Railroad to pay the interest on their government loan; correspondence from William McAdoo to Keating re possible endorsement of U.S.G. Cherry for U.S. Senate; copy of summary of minutes of the 4th annual conference of Editor's Official Railroad Labor Magazine; correspondence from Keep to Keating re Keep quitting his job with the O.R.T.; between Keating and Venable re working conditions on the M&NA Railroad and some news clippings.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  May 2nd-29th; Advertisement re "Buy a Farm" attached correspondence (unsigned) to the First National Bank re the turning over of funds to the Michigan Federation of Farm Loan Associations, additional correspondence re Senator Couzens; correspondence between Keating and Keep re probabilities for a 3rd party political movement; correspondence from Keating to E.K. Derrickson re in appreciation for Derrickson support in getting Cleveland convention to go for labor conventions; miscellaneous correspondence re Keating's planned trip to Cleveland.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  June 2nd-24th; Routine correspondence re payment of subscription contracts; from Keep to Keating re 3rd party politics and non-voters; from Sen. Lafollette Jr. to Keating re the Cleveland convention; article from Harrison Times entitled "Railroad is Menaced by Barkley Bill,; Order of Railroad Telegraphers Report of Proceedings, May 23, 1924 correspondence from White Moore, Attorney to Keating re_ action against Labor for libel in Mack-Miller Candle Co. case, also contains complaint in said case before the FTC; correspondence from Keating to Herman E. Wills, giving a categorical dealing with all the issues of the delegation; from Spencer Miller Jr. (Secretary of Workers Education Bureau) to Keating re possible future connection between English and American liberal newspapers; correspondence from Keating to White & Moore re the Mack-Miller Candle Co. case and a possible law suit for libel; correspondence from H.S. Jeffrey to the shareholders of the Mechanics and Merchants Bank re a request for contributions per share to recoup lost money in a lawsuit against the railroad leadership.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)